[
  {
    "question": "If you pitched up in the Seneca, what would happen to the blade angle?",
    "answer": "If you pitch up in a Seneca the speed IAS will decrease, because of the constant speed drive (in the propeller hub).\n\nThe propellers want to maintain the original RPM. Therefore the blades will go to a more fine blade setting.",
    "id": "cb492ac6-3996-4a18-823a-baf4bd551291"
  },
  {
    "question": "What are the longitudinal ridges on the stabilator of the Seneca for?",
    "id": "d5cfaef3-e45d-47bb-914e-eab890517280"
  },
  {
    "question": "What ice protection systems does the Seneca have?",
    "id": "761c82c1-6556-49f5-8ee9-8a7b1e4d6d20"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the Engine Failure After Take off drill on your previous aircraft?",
    "id": "bd14a4bb-9809-4172-87a9-b733c5f83cd8"
  },
  {
    "question": "If you slammed the throttles wide open during takeoff on the Seneca, what would happen?",
    "id": "c78a32f7-5473-45f5-86af-1273701387dd"
  },
  {
    "question": "Does the Seneca have a carb heat system?",
    "answer": "No, Seneca has a fuel injection system therefore it does not have a carburator.",
    "id": "27745319-e310-442a-a9c1-3647e9893aac"
  },
  {
    "question": "What indications would you get inside the cockpit when overboosting the engine of a Seneca?",
    "id": "f85f70ed-9efb-4347-a374-52cdd6065c4e"
  },
  {
    "question": "Do you get carb icing in the Seneca?",
    "answer": "No, Seneca has a fuel injection system which doesn’t suffer from vapour icing.",
    "id": "8e9ee4c2-7213-45c3-be9a-2171466d7de1"
  },
  {
    "question": "What color of fuel is used in the Seneca?",
    "answer": "Seneca uses MOGAS (red) or AVGAS (Blue)",
    "id": "cd34ecf2-05ff-4608-bb70-68e372282e5a"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the endurance of a Seneca?",
    "id": "412f9611-b2e0-4249-a4ac-f1116ffa341f"
  },
  {
    "question": "Where the brakes and gear hydraulically operated on the Seneca?",
    "answer": "Only hydraulic gear.",
    "id": "623c5260-9bc8-43a9-992e-a572adf8caac"
  },
  {
    "question": "If whilst taking off in a Seneca you lose the left engine what side do you want the crosswind to come from?",
    "answer": "Live side to oppose the yawing moment. In this case, the right side.",
    "id": "80a6c184-a44c-42a8-ac97-e38915b6a1b6"
  },
  {
    "question": "When you feather the engine on the Seneca, do you have to feather before a certain RPM?",
    "answer": "Yes, feathering locks engage at 800 RPM on the Seneca.\n\nWe feather to stop windmilling and reduce drag.",
    "id": "666129de-7844-49d8-accf-8ec7bf6afbca"
  },
  {
    "question": "Why can't you feather the propellers below 800 RPM on the Seneca?",
    "answer": "Because the feathering locks engage at 800 RPM.",
    "id": "9ddd6175-5b25-4b67-918d-ea0ee11c53a2"
  },
  {
    "question": "Tell me about the V speeds in a Seneca",
    "answer": "V speed in a Seneca:\n\nVr = 77kts\n\nVx = 76kts\n\nVy = 89kts\n\nVyse = 89kts\n\nVmca = 68kts\n\nVne = 195kts\n\nVno = 163kts\n\nVa = 121kts",
    "id": "1126fcd0-790e-480f-bb6d-8e23f51e4df7"
  },
  {
    "question": "How is the start generated in the Seneca?",
    "answer": "The start is generated by the starter motor, which is powered by the battery.",
    "id": "a964f770-d047-4006-9e0b-170faad15b71"
  },
  {
    "question": "What's the purpose of the mirror looking at the nose-wheel on a Seneca?",
    "id": "18e20cb9-3fbf-4139-b196-9111dfa97b07"
  },
  {
    "question": "You’ve been flying the Seneca, does it have a critical engine?",
    "answer": "Yes, the left engine is the critical engine because the propellers rotate clockwise.",
    "id": "10dbee0a-b710-4356-869e-ef049e0929c8"
  },
  {
    "question": "How do the pneumatic de-icing devices on the Seneca work?",
    "id": "b9d1bd7c-0474-481b-9987-fa8764fa4e78"
  },
  {
    "question": "Give a calculation to work out how far a Seneca could fly with a certain amount of fuel.",
    "answer": "Amount of fuel divided by 24 GPH (gallons of fuel per hour).",
    "id": "9d72fd4b-475c-4093-81b5-e7a9c74759a5"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the maximum crosswind limit on a Seneca?",
    "answer": "17KTS",
    "id": "1eff66b4-09f8-4202-a1d3-4e3d0db378f7"
  },
  {
    "question": "Where the brakes and gear hydraulically operated on the Seneca?",
    "answer": "Only hydraulic gear.",
    "id": "623c5260-9bc8-43a9-992e-a572adf8caac"
  }
]
